Guide to the Asian Garment Workers in New York City Oral History Collection OH.018
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Asian Garment Workers in New York City Oral History Collection
1989-2004
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Nguyen, Bichiluyen
Chin, Winifred C., 1952-
New York University. Asian/Pacific/American Studies Program and Institute
OH.018
1 Linear Feet in 1 CD box and 1 half manuscript box
7 audiocassettes
The collection consists of interviews of garment workers who came to New York City from Vietnam, China, the Philippines, and California. Interviews are primarily with International Ladies Garment Workers' Union members and staff (especially Local 23-25) and its successor organization the Union of Needletrades, Industrial and Textile Employees (UNITE), but one interview is with a garment manufacturer. Topics covered include emigration to the United States, working conditions, joining the ILGWU, major strikes, the effects of globalization on the garment industry and unions, and unique challenges in organizing in the Asian-American community. The majority of the interviews were taken in 1989 by Bichiluyen Nguyen of NYU's History Department. Interviews were taken in English, Chinese or Vietnamese, and indexes or transcripts exist in English for all interviews.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Bichiluyen Nguyen donated the interviews with Paul Bui, Shui Mak Ka, Connie Ling, Katie Quan, and Kieu Tran in 1989. "The Asian-American Labor Movement: An Oral History of the Organization of the Chinatown Garment Shops" and the Muzaffar Chishti interview were deposited with Tamiment by Winifred Chin and the Asian/Pacific/American Institute in 2004. The accession numbers associated with this collection are 1950.056 and 2014.005.
Arrangement
Access compact disks are arranged alphabetically. Original cassettes, indexes, and transcripts are arranged according to an archivist-devised numbering system.
Historical Note
NYU undergraduate Bichiluyen Nguyen, herself a Vietnamese immigrant, conducted five of the interviews as part of an internship in the History Department in 1989. In 2003, five additional interviews regarding the labor movement in the Chinatown garment shops were taken by Winifred Chin, a visiting scholar at the Asian/Pacific/American Institute.
Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures
Access CDs for some audiovisual materials in the collection are available by appointment for reading room viewing and listening only. Other audiovisual materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers. Materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact Tamiment Library & Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, special.collections@nyu.edu, 212-998-2596 with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
Related Archival Materials
The audio for the interviews with Jay Mazur, Edgar Romney, and May Chen can be found in the collection New Yorkers at Work (OH 001).
May Chen Papers (WAG 301)
Tung Pok Chin and Wing Fong Chin Papers and Photographs (TAM 235)
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of 6 audio recordings and their transcripts of interviews with garment workers who came to New York City from Vietnam, China, the Philippines, and California. Interviews are primarily with International Ladies Garment Workers' Union members and staff (especially Local 23-25) and its successor organization, the Union of Needletrades, Industrial, and Textile Employees (UNITE). One interview is with a garment manufacturer. Topics covered include emigration to the United States, working conditions, joining the ILGWU, major strikes, the impacts of globalization, and unique challenges in organizing in the Asian-American community.
Asian Americans -- Economic conditions.; Asian Americans -- Employment.; Immigrants -- United States.; Clothing workers -- Labor unions -- New York (State) -- New York.; Clothing workers -- New York (N.Y.); International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union; New York University. Asian/Pacific/American Studies Program and Institute
- Paul Bui, March 15, 1989; cuid44045
  Scope and Content Note
  Interview includes discussion of Bui's youth in Vietnam, immigration to the United States, the clothing business that Bui owned in the Bronx, and his views on challenges contracting with clients and negotiating with unions.
  - Original Recording (Box 1, Cassette 3)
  - Transcript (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Muzaffar Chishti, May 21, 2004; cuid44046
  The interview discusses Chishti's work with undocumented workers during his years as director of the Immigration Project at the ILGWU. Topics include the union's activities to aid such workers, social and legal concerns, and lobbying activities.
  - Original Recording (Box 1, Cassette 6)
  - Access Copy (Box 1, Cd 2)
  - Transcript (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Shui Mak Ka, April 25, 1989; cuid44047
  Interview includes discussion of Ka's youth and education in China and Hong Kong and her work in the People's Republic of China there as a doctor. Also covered are different working conditions in textile industry in Chicago and New York, strikes in early 1980s, disputes with Italians, and worker wages.
  - Original Recording (Box 1, Cassette 4A-B)
  - Access Copy (Box 1, Cd 3-5)
  - Transcript (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Connie Ling, May 12, 1989; cuid44048
  Scope and Contents
  Interview includes discussion of youth in Philippines and Hong Kong, immigration to United States, activities as a business agent for union, and strike in Chinatown shops.
  Existence and Location of Originals
  A physical tape and access copy of this interview was not found in the collection (10/2024).
  - Transcript (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Katie Quan, April 20, 1989; cuid44049
  Interview includes discussion of strikes in the 1980s, union's education department, Coalition of Labor Union Women, new immigrants, and real estate in New York City and Chinatown.
  - Original Recording (Box 1, Cassette 5)
  - Access Copy (Box 1, Cd 6-7)
  - Transcript (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Kieu Tran, March 15, 1989; cuid44050
  Topics discussed include youth in Vietnam, conditions in factories and for textiles workers who work at home, wages, and employment with Paul Bui's Princess Mai Company.
  - Original Recording (Box 1, Cassette 2)
  - Access Copy (Box 1, Cd 8)
  - Transcript (Box 2, Folder 2)
- "The Asian-American Labor Movement: An Oral History of the Organization of the Chinatown Garment Shops" (Includes interviews with Jay Mazur, Wing Fong Chin, Edgar Romney, and May Chen), March 2004; cuid44051
  "The Asian-American Labor Movement: An Oral History of the Organization of the Chinatown Garment Shops" is a four-interview project compiled by Winifred Chin, a visiting scholar at New York University's Asian/Pacific/American Institute. The resulting document contains transcribed interviews with Jay Mazur, Wing Fong Chin, Edgar Romney, and May Chen, all who were involved with UNITE or its predecessor ILGWU. It also includes Jay Mazur's "Globalization and Governance" and "Globalization's Dark Side" as attachments. Subjects discussed include the 1982 labor rally in Columbus Park, the effects of globalization on the garment industry and unions, and unique challenges in organizing in the Asian-American community. An audio recording of the interview with Wing Fong Chin is also available.
  - Original Recording (Box 1, Cassette 7)
  - Access Copy (Box 1, Cd 9)
  - Transcript (Box 2, Folder 7)